dmaresponsibility.org 2017-02-04

# Privacy Policy | thedma.org

[Home](https://thedma.org/) » Privacy Policy

**DMA’s Online Privacy Policy for Members and Business Visitors**  
Effective May 9, 2012

## DMA’s Online Privacy Policy for Businesses

#### General Statement of Privacy

The Data & Marketing Association respects the privacy of its members and of those who visit this site.

This Privacy Policy applies to business visitors visiting the websites of the Data & Marketing Association

Attention Consumers: Consumers can find information to help them with their marketing preferences, including how to register for DMA’s Preference Services, at www.DMAChoice.org and can also contact us via email at Consumer@the-dma.org if they wish to learn more. The DMA does not engage in marketing to consumers and does not maintain consumer marketing data, rather, it offers consumers ways to manage their preferences via DMAchoice.org.

#### Information We Collect

When you visit one of the DMA websites mentioned above, our Web server automatically recognizes the domain name of your computer or Web-enabled device. We collect information that you share when you complete an online registration form or make postings to bulletin boards or chat areas on our sites or via other website transactions. This information may include, but is not limited to, your name, company name, company address, phone number, fax number, email address and payment information (e.g., encrypted credit card number and billing address).

When you sign on to our websites or make a purchase, we will collect the additional contact and payment information, payment history, profile and preference information that you provide.

We collect the email addresses of those who purchase goods or services from us and supply us with their email address.

We may also collect information on what pages users access or visit, as described below.

#### Use of Information by DMA and Others

DMA uses information collected about visitors to our websites to:

  * fulfill purchase and other requests made by visitors;
  * provide benefits of membership, including non-promotional DMA communications;
  * improve the content of our websites;
  * customize the content and/or layout of Web pages for individual visitors;
  * contact members and those who visit our sites about new DMA products and
  * services or upcoming events;
  * notify visitors about updates to our websites;
  * contact visitors for marketing purposes;
  * disclose information, when legally required to do so, at the request of governmental authorities conducting an investigation; and to
  * verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing our websites and applicable laws, or to protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our websites.

DMA may share information collected through our websites with agents or contractors authorized solely to perform services on our behalf, such as providing support for our internal operations.

From time to time, DMA may also share information collected through our websites with other reputable third-party organizations whose products or services we feel may be of interest to you or to deliver on our behalf DMA advertisements to you on other Websites you visit. However, please note that we do not share email addresses with third-party organizations for their marketing purposes, instead, we may occasionally send you messages from reputable third-parties on their behalf, and you will be able to opt-out of future third party offers if you choose to opt-out as set forth below.

We do not rent email addresses to third-party organizations.

#### Use of Cookies and Browser-Level Information

A “cookie” is a small piece of information that a website can store in a designated file on your computer or Web-enabled device. Cookies can be used, among other things, to identify your computer or device when you log into a website and may track your IP address in order to do so.

When you visit our websites, we use cookies to collect aggregate information on the number of visitors to our site and the number of pages viewed. While DMA does analysis of its website logs to monitor the flow of traffic and make improvements to the site’s content, its website logs are not personally identifiable, and no attempt is made to link them to individual visitors to this site. This information is used only by DMA and its agents or contractors and is not shared with any third-party companies.

If you register through one of our websites, we place a unique identifier cookie that is used to maintain your “sign on” status for the duration of your visit to the site, customize or tailor your visit and to store your user preferences for that site over time. We also use cookies to track the pages visited so that we can deliver DMA Web content based on a visitor’s profile (as provided by the visitor) and the visitor’s past activity on that site. The use of these cookies also enables our sites to “remember” the items that visitors add to their shopping carts as they browse elsewhere on the site, to alert visitors to new areas that we think might be of interest to them when they return to the site, to ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, and to customize the Web page content based on a visitor’s browser type or other information that the visitor sends.

#### Choices About Data Collection and Use

We may allow advertisements to be placed on our websites by third-party organizations. Those organizations may collect web-reporting data on their placed advertisements.

If you do not wish to receive information about new DMA products and services, third party offers we may send you, or upcoming events, you may opt-out of receiving promotional DMA communications by sending an email request to customer@the-dma.org. In your email, please indicate which mode(s) of communication you would like to opt-out of (postal mail, email or telephone contact). If you are visiting other Websites and see an advertisement from the DMA, there will be an opportunity to opt-out of future DMA ads on that site as managed by the third party provider through its opt-out function.

Please note that DMA members who opt-out of promotional DMA communications will continue to receive non-promotional DMA communications via email and otherwise that are provided as conditions of membership. If you would like to opt-out of individual DMA member publications, please contact DMA Customer Service at 212.790.1500 or via email customer@the-dma.org. If you do not wish to have your information shared with third party companies as previously described, please send an email request to customer@the-dma.org indicating such. We will be sure your name is removed from the list we share with other organizations.

You can also contact us by mail or phone:

The Data & Marketing Association  
1333 Broadway, Suite 301  
New York, NY 10018  
(212) 768-7277 Extension 1500

Visitors can also choose not to accept cookies. Your Web browser may alert and permit you to refuse cookies. Please check with the company operating your browser for more information on how to change those browser-level settings. Please note that disabling cookies for some services may affect your ability to use that service.

#### Access and Correction

Upon your request, we will provide you with the opportunity to review and correct the contact and payment information that we maintain about you. We will accommodate all reasonable requests. If you wish to review the accuracy of the information you have provided, please send an email request to customer@the-dma.org.

#### Security

We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving payment and other sensitive data. We have security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from or about you.

#### Changes to This Privacy Policy

From time to time, we may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. Any material changes to this privacy policy will be communicated to users through this Web page, so please be sure to visit this page periodically.

#### Questions

Please be assured that we take your concerns about privacy quite seriously, and we intend to take every reasonable effort to protect your privacy. If you have any questions about DMA’s privacy practices, please contact DMA’s Corporate & Social Responsibility Department:

Attention: Privacy Policy Compliance  
1615 L Street NW, Suite 1100  
Washington, DC 20036  
ethics@the-dma.org  
Fax: (202) 955-0085

## DMA’s Online Privacy Policy for Consumers

**DMA Headquarters**  
Data & Marketing Association, Inc.  
1333 Broadway, Suite 301  
New York, NY 10018

**DMA Washington Office**  
Data & Marketing Association, Inc.  
1615 L Street NW; Suite 1100  
Washington, DC 20036-5624

DMA contracts with IMS to provide the following consumer services:

  1. Removing your name from mailing lists
  2. Removing your name from email lists
  3. Removing deceased individuals’ names from lists
  4. Removing the names of individuals in your care from lists
  5. Removing your name from telemarketing lists

All personally identifiable information collected by registration for these services is used to implement your preferences only. The DMA does not sell consumer mailing or emailing lists.

#### Questions?

If you are a consumer and would like more information, or if you are having trouble registering for DMAchoice, please contact us.  
If you are a business and have questions about how to subscribe to these services, here is some more helpful information.

#### Cookies

We place cookies on all website visitor hard drives to collect information on the number of visitors to our site and the number of pages viewed. It is also used to provide relevant information to our visitors and for website and system administration, including research and development, user analysis and business decision-making. Cookie information is used only by the DMA and our agents. It is not provided to any other organization.

#### Clickstream Data

We collect clickstream data and HTTP protocol elements through access logs. This information is not personally identifiable and is used for website and system administration, including research and development, user analysis and business decision-making.

#### Security

We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving data. We have security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from or about you.

#### Accountability

If you feel that DMAchoice, or any website, is not living up to its stated information policy, you may contact the DMA’s Department of Corporate Responsibility by email at ethics@the-dma.org
